# Le Duc Khai Last updated: March 15, 2024

Toronto, Canada Permanent Resident in Canada GitHub | LinkedIn | Google Scholar duckhai.le@mail.utoronto.ca | (+1) 437 249 2462

#### Research Interest

My current research spans all aspects of semi-supervised learning (speech/text/vision/time-series), in which I have been bringing research to real-world business scenarios. To provide cheap medical care for the poor, I am interested in developing machine learning algorithms that serve medical purposes, e.g. in medical imaging, bio-signals, tele-medicine, natural language processing, and so on.

#### Education

#### University of Toronto

Toronto, Canada

Master of Applied Science in Biomedical Engineering

January 2024 – Present

- The university was ranked 1st in Canada, 12th in the world in Computer Science, and 15th in Medicine (QS Rankings)
- Research area: Machine Learning for Multivariate Time-series
- Supervisor: Prof. Shehroz Khan (h-index 26)

## **RWTH Aachen University**

Aachen, Germany

Bachelor Thesis in Computer Science

December 2022

- The university was ranked 2nd in Germany and 50th in the world in Computer Science (THE Rankings)
- Thesis supervisor: Prof. Hermann Ney (h-index 113), Prof. Ralf Schlüter (h-index 50)
- Thesis title: Unsupervised Pre-Training for Vietnamese Automatic Speech Recognition in the HYKIST Project [DOI]
- Thesis grade: 1.0/6.0 (German grade), 100/100 (International percentage)

# FH Aachen University of Applied Sciences

lülich, Germany

Bachelor in Biomedical Engineering, taught-in-German program

December 2022

- The university was ranked 1st among Universities of Applied Sciences in Germany in Engineering and Informatics (WiWo Ranking)
- Thesis supervisor: Prof. Ilya Digel (h-index 23)
- Overall grade: 2.2/6.0 (German grade), 80/100 (International percentage)

# Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

October 2016

Bachelor in International Economic Relations

- The university was ranked 1st overall in Vietnam and 701-750th in the world (OS Rankings)
- Top 100 out of 354897 candidates (0.02%) with total scores of 27/30 in the Vietnamese National High School Graduation Examination 2015 in Mathematics, Physics and English
- Grade: 1st ranked Valedictorian

#### Research Experience

## University Health Network

Toronto, Canada

Graduate Research Assistant

January 2024 – Present

- University Health Network is ranked as the world's 5th best hospital (Newsweek 2023) and ranked 1st in rehabilitation.
- Research project: Predicting Agitation in People Living with Dementia

## Machine Learning and Human Language Technology Group, RWTH Aachen University

Aachen, Germany

Student Research Assistant

May 2021 - Present

- Research supervisor: Prof. Hermann Ney (h-index 113, 63000+ citations, the most cited researcher and the highest h-index in the
  world in Speech Recognition and in Machine Translation)
- Research co-supervisor: Prof. Ralf Schlüter (h-index 50, 12000+ citations)
- Research topics: Semi-Supervised Learning for Medical Speech Recognition

#### FH Aachen University of Applied Sciences

Geilenkirchen, Germany

Research Intern

January 2016 - March 2016

- Research labs: Freshman Laboratory of Electrical Engineering, Laboratory of Molecular Medicine and Cell, Biophysics Lab, Chemistry Laboratory, and Freshman Biomedical Labor
- · Received certificates for contribution

# (\*) Equal contribution

# 7. Speech Sentiment Analysis for Healthcare

<u>Khai Le-Duc</u>\*, Khai-Nguyen Nguyen\*, Long Vo-Dang, Truong-Son Hy Anonymity period, submitted to MLHC 2024

#### 6. Vietnamese-English Machine Translation for Medical Conversations

<u>Khai Le-Duc</u>\*, Hung-Phong Tran, Long Vo-Dang, Khai-Nguyen Nguyen, Truong-Son Hy Anonymity period, submitted to MLHC 2024

#### 5. Real-time Speech Summarization for Medical Conversations

<u>Khai Le-Duc</u>\*, Khai-Nguyen Nguyen\*, Long Vo-Dang, Truong-Son Hy Anonymity period, submitted to Interspeech 2024

# 4. VietMed-NER: Medical Named Entity Recognition from Speech

<u>Khai Le-Duc</u>, David Thulke, Hung-Phong Tran, Long Vo-Dang, Ralf Schlüter Public preprint comes soon, submitted to ACL 2024

# 3. Dynamic Intermediate Loss for Fine-tuning Self-Supervised Models

<u>Khai Le-Duc</u>\*, Christoph Lüscher\*, Ralf Schlüter Anonymity period, submitted to Interspeech 2024

# 2. VietMed: A Dataset and Benchmark for Automatic Speech Recognition of Vietnamese in the Medical Domain Khai Le-Duc\*, Christoph Lüscher\*, Minh-Nghia Phan, Ralf Schlüter Accepted at LREC-COLING 2024

# 1. Development of Hybrid ASR Systems for Low Resource Medical Domain Conversational Telephone Speech Christoph Lüscher, Mohammad Zeineldeen, Zijian Yang, Peter Vieting, <u>Khai Le-Duc</u>, Weiyue Wang, Ralf Schlüter, Hermann Ney

ITG Speech Communication 2023

#### Awards & Honors

10.01.03	
ORT Conference Participation Award	2024
University Health Network	500 CAD
Top 12 HackerRank in Germany	2020
HackerRank - the largest competitive programming platform in the world	
Valedictorian Scholarship of Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City	2015
Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City	

# Selected Open-Source Projects

# **Demo for Multilingual Speech Translation**

- The first free-of-charge medical speech translation API in the world, being deployed on cloud in German medical centers to support conversations between German doctors and international patients without language barriers
- Co-contributor of the demo

#### **Awesome Competitive Programming Problems**

- Curated extensive library of Python data structures and algorithms specifically designed for competitive programming contests
- Solved various problems including String Manipulation, Graph Theory, Greedy, Dynamic Programming, Sliding Window, Mathematics and Recursion
- On GitHub top 1 trending, received 170+ stars

# Other Experience

# Mathnasium

October 2023 – November 2023

Instructor - Part time Toronto, Canada

• Communicated with students in an understandable way about daily lessons

Developed automated teaching tools and methods to help students learn mathematics

Techniker Krankenkasse

March 2016 – June 2016

Volunteer - Full time

Geilenkirchen, Germany

• The company is Germany's largest health insurance fund

- Maintained business contacts with 1000+ student customers, organized and executed 3 events to advertise company's insurance packages, and created marketing concepts
- · Received certificate for contribution

# Programming skills:

- Programming Languages: Python, MATLAB, Java (basic)
- Databases (basic): Snowflake, SQL, MongoDB
- Deep Learning Frameworks: Keras, Tensorflow, Pytorch, Fairseq, HuggingFace
- Data Science Libraries: NumPy, SciKit-Learn, Pandas, SciPy, Seaborn, Matplotlib
- Data Analysis and Statistical Tools (basic): SPSS, Excel
- Image Processing Libraries: OpenCV, scikit-image
- Operating Systems: Linux, Git
- Document Preparation: LaTeX, Markdown

<u>Relevant courseworks</u>: Medical Statistics, Information Processing, Image Processing, Medical Computer Science, Introducing MATLAB, Introducing to Python.

Spoken languages: Vietnamese (Native), English (IELTS 7.0), German (C1)